<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Chapter I: The Project</title>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Conversion from Juxta comparison set to TEI-conformant markup</resp>
                    <name>Generated by Juxta Commons</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><p/></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc><p/></sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <variantEncoding location="internal" method="parallel-segmentation"/>
        </encodingDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <front>
            <div>
                <listWit>
                    <witness xml:id="wit-5554">Ch. 1 The Project 1861</witness>
                    <witness xml:id="wit-5553">Ch. 1 The Project 1859</witness>
                </listWit>
            </div>
        </front>
        <body>
            <p>On one of those exciting occasions, during a contest for the Presidency of the United States, a number of gentlemen met in the city of Baltimore. They were few in number, and appeared little concerned about the affairs of the general government. Though men of intelligence, their time and attention 
                <app>
                    <rdg wit="#wit-5554">seemed</rdg>
                    <rdg wit="#wit-5553">appeared</rdg>
                </app> to be entirely absorbed in an adventure of self interest. They met for the purpose of completing arrangements for refitting the old ship &apos;Merchantman,&apos; which then lay in the harbor near Fell&apos;s Point. Colonel Stephen Franks, Major James Armsted, Captain Richard Paul and Captain George 
                <app>
                    <rdg wit="#wit-5554">Rayer</rdg>
                    <rdg wit="#wit-5553">Royer</rdg>
                </app> , composed those who represented the American side&#8212;Captain Juan Garcia and Captain Jose Castello, those of Cuban interest.<lb/>
                Here a conversation ensued upon what seemed a point of vital importance to the company; it related to the place best suited for the completion of their arrangements. The Americans insisted on Baltimore as affording the greatest facilities, and having done more for the encouragement and protection of the trade, than any other known place. Whilst the Cubans on the other side, urged their objections on the ground that the continual increase of liberal principles in the various political parties, which were fast ushering into existence, made the objection beyond a controversy. Havana was contended for as a point best suited for adjusting their arrangements, and that too with many apparent reasons; but for some cause, the preference for Baltimore prevailed.<lb/>
                Subsequently to the adjustment of their affairs by the most complete arrangement for refitting the vessel, Col. Franks took leave of the party for his home in the distant State of Mississippi.<lb/>
            </p>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
